<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Anno Regni Caroli II regis Angliæ, Scotiæ, Franciæ &amp; Hiberniæ, vicesimo secundo &amp; vicesimo tertio at the Parliament begun at Westminster the eighth day of May, Anno Dom. 1661. In the thirteenth year of the regin of our most gracious sovereign Lord Charles by the grace of God, of England, Scotland, France and Ireland King, defender of the faith, &amp;c., and there continued by several prorogations, to the fourteenth day of February 1669/70, and thence continued to the 22th of April 1671 on which day the said Parliament was prorogued to the 16th day of April which shall be in the year 1672.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Laws, statutes, etc.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09030</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E1120A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R175040</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">62369208</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 62369208</idno>
            <idno type="VID">187888</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09030)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 187888)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2848:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Anno Regni Caroli II regis Angliæ, Scotiæ, Franciæ &amp; Hiberniæ, vicesimo secundo &amp; vicesimo tertio at the Parliament begun at Westminster the eighth day of May, Anno Dom. 1661. In the thirteenth year of the regin of our most gracious sovereign Lord Charles by the grace of God, of England, Scotland, France and Ireland King, defender of the faith, &amp;c., and there continued by several prorogations, to the fourteenth day of February 1669/70, and thence continued to the 22th of April 1671 on which day the said Parliament was prorogued to the 16th day of April which shall be in the year 1672.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Laws, statutes, etc.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>12 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Charles Bill and Thomas Newcomb,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCXC. [1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title vignette: royal coat of arms.</note>
                  <note>Text in black letter.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Debt relief --  Great Britain --  Law and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Debt, imprisonment for --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1660-1714 --  Sources.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Charles II, 1660-1685 --  Sources.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:187888:1"/>
            <p>Anno Regni CAROLI II. REGIS. <hi>Angliae, Scotiae, Franciae &amp;
Hiberniae,</hi> Viceſimo ſecundo &amp; viceſimo tertio</p>
            <p>At the Parliament begun at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the Eighth day
of <hi>May, Anno Dom.</hi> 1661. In the Thirteenth Year of the Reign of our
moſt Gracious Sovereign Lord <hi>Charles,</hi> by the Grace of God, of
<hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> King, Defender of the
Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And there continued by ſeveral Prorogations, to the Fourteenth
day of <hi>February,</hi> 1669/70.</p>
            <p>And thence continued to the 22th of <hi>April</hi> 1671. On which
day the ſaid Parliament was Prorogued to the 16th day of <hi>April</hi> which
ſhall be in the year 1672.</p>
            <figure>
               <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               <figDesc>royal English blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>Charles Bill</hi> and <hi>Thomas
Newcomb,</hi> Printers to the King and Queens moſt Excellent Majeſties.
MDCXC.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="Act_of_Parliament">
            <div type="Act">
               <pb facs="tcp:187888:2"/>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:187888:2"/>
               <head>Anno XXII &amp; XXIII. CAROLI II. REGIS. An Act for the Relief and Releaſe of Poor Diſtreſſed
Priſoners for Debt.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Oraſmuch as very many Perſons now Detained in Priſon,
are miſerably Impoveriſhed, either by reaſon of the late unhappy Times,
the ſad and dreadful Fire, their own Misfortunes, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, ſo as
they are totally diſabled to give any Satisfaction to their Creditors, and
ſo become, without Advantage to any, a Charge and Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>then to the Kingdom,
and by Noiſomneſs (inſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parably incident to extream Poverty) may be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come
the occaſion of Peſtilence and Contagious Diſeaſes, to the great
Prejudice of the Kingdom; Be it therefore En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by the Kings moſt
Excellent Majeſty, by and with the Advice and Conſent of the Lords
Spiritual and Temporal, and the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons in this preſent Parliament
Aſſembled, and by the Authority of the ſame, That it ſhall and may be
lawful to and for any Iuſtice of the Peace of any County, City, Town or
Liberty within the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> or
Town of <hi>Berwick</hi> upon <hi>Tweed,</hi> by Warrant under his Hand and
Seal, to require the Sheriff, Goal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, or Keeper of any Priſon within his
reſpective Iurisdiction, to bring without delay, the Body of any Perſon,
being in Priſon for Debt on the Fourteenth day of <hi>April,</hi> One
thouſand ſix hundred ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and one, or Damages (and Petitioning ſuch
Iuſtice to be Diſchar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged) to ſome convenient Place within the diſtance
of One mile from the ſaid Priſon, and ſhall certifie the Cauſe and
Cauſes of the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſonment, before the ſame Iuſtice; Which Warrant
every ſuch Sheriff, Goaler and Keeper is hereby commanded to obey.</p>
               <p>And in caſe ſuch Priſoner coming before ſuch Iuſtice,
ſhall take an Oath to this effect; <hi>(Viz.)</hi>
               </p>
               <q>
                  <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <div type="oath">
                           <p>
                              <hi>I <hi>A. B.</hi> do upon my Corporal Oath Solemnly
Profeſs and Declare before Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mighty God, That I have not any Eſtate Real
or Perſonal, in Poſſeſſion, Rever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, or Remainder, of the Value
of Ten pounds in the whole, or ſufficient to pay the Debt or Damages for
which I am Impriſoned; And that I have not directly, or indirectly Sold,
Leaſed, or otherwiſe Conveyed, Diſpoſed of, or Entruſted all or any
Part of my Eſtate, thereby to Secure the ſame, to receive or expect any
Profit or Advantage thereof, or Defraud or Deceive any Creditor or Creditors
whatſoever, to whom I ſtand Indebted.</hi>
                           </p>
                        </div>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </q>
               <p>Then after the taking of ſuch Oath, the ſaid Iuſtice
ſhall Remand the Priſoner to Priſon, and ſhall give a Certificate there
of in Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting under his Hand and Seal, to the ſame Priſoner, to be
ſerved up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on ſuch Perſon or Perſons, his, or her Executors or
Adminiſtrators, <pb n="4" facs="tcp:187888:3"/>or to be left at the place of the uſual
abode of ſuch Perſon or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons at whoſe Suit the Priſoner
ſtandeth Charged and Impriſoned, thereby appointing as well the ſaid
Perſon or Perſons, as the ſaid Priſoner, to appear before the
Iuſtices at the next General Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Seſſions of the Peace to be holden
for the ſame County, City, Town, or Liberty; When if it ſhall appear upon
Oath (which Oath the ſaid Iuſtices are Impowered to Adminiſter) that the
ſaid Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate was ſo ſerved or left Fourty days or more before the
ſaid Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons; And that the ſaid Oath taken by the ſaid Priſoner,
be not diſpro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved by good Teſtimony of any credible Perſon or Perſons
upon Oath, to be adminiſtred by the ſaid Iuſtices, by virtue of this Act;
Then the ſaid Iuſtices being ſatisfied therein, ſhall direct there
War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant under their Hands and Seals, commanding the ſaid Sheriff, Goaler, or
Keeper of the Priſon, to ſet at Liberty, and Diſcharge the ſaid
Priſoner, if Impriſoned for the Cauſes aforeſaid, and no o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther,
without paying any thing for Fee, or Chamber-Rent; which Warrant ſhall be a
ſufficient Diſcharge to the ſame Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Priſon,
and no Action of Eſcape, or other Action, ſhall be brought againſt them,
or any of them, for the ſame in any wiſe.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, and be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid,
Tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> when ſuch Priſoner
or Priſoners for Debt ſhall have Legally taken the ſaid Oath in this Act
propoſed to be taken, and ſhall have duly Summoned his or their Creditor or
Creditors; And after the ſaid Fourty days time, if the ſaid Creditor or
Creditors ſhall make no Diſcovery of his, her, or their Eſtates, nor
diſprove nor detect the ſaid Priſoner or Priſoners of Forſwearing
themſelves; That then if ſuch Creditor or Creditors will not be ſatisfied
therewith, (that the ſaid Priſoner or Priſoners may be ſet at Liberty)
or will inſiſt to have the ſaid Priſoner continued in Goal, That then
the ſaid Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditor or Creditors ſhall at his and their own proper Coſts
and Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, allow and pay Weekly a reaſonable Maintenance to the ſaid
Priſoner or Priſoners, ſuch as the ſaid Commiſſioners of the Peace,
or any Three of them, in their reſpective Diviſions, ſhall order and
appoint, not exceeding Eighteen pence a Week; and upon Nonpay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the
ſame Weekly the ſaid Priſoner or Priſoners ſhall be ſet at Liberty,
according to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That
upon a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Action of Eſcape, or other Suit, brought or to be brought againſt
any Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of any ſuch Priſon, or other Officer or
Perſon, for any thing done in Obedience to this Act, it ſhall and may be
lawful to and forſuch Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Priſon, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
Officer or Perſon, to Plead the General Iſſue, and give this Act in
Evidence, which ſhall be a good and ſufficient Diſcharge, and ſhall
ſave harmleſs every ſuch Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Priſon Plead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
the ſame; And if the Plaintiff in any ſuch Action ſhall be Nonſuit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed,
or Verdict paſs againſt him, the Defendant ſhall have double Coſts, to
be Taxed by the Court where ſuch Action ſhall be brought.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it further Enacted by the Authority
afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That notwithſtanding the Diſcharge of the Perſon of ſuch
Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, as aforeſaid, upon taking the Oath aforeſaid, all and every
Iudg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment had and taken againſt him or her, ſhall be, and ſtand good and
eff<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ctual in the Law, to all
intents and purpoſes againſt the Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods and
Chattels only of the ſaid Priſoner ſo Diſcharged as aforeſaid; And it
ſhall and may be lawful to and for ſuch Creditor of ſuch Priſoner or
Priſoners ſo Diſcharged <pb n="5" facs="tcp:187888:3"/>as aforeſaid, his Executors,
Adminiſtrators or Aſſigns, to take out any new Execution againſt the
Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods and Chattels of ſuch Priſoner or
Priſoners (his or her wear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Apparel, Bedding for him and his or her
Family, and Tools ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary for his or her Trade and Occupation only
excepted) for the ſatisfaction of his or their ſaid Debt, in ſuch ſort,
manner and form, as he or they might have done, if the perſon or perſons of
ſuch Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner or Priſoners had never been taken in Execution; Any Act,
Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute or Cuſtom to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, and be it further Enacted by the Authority
aforeſaid, That if at any time after the taking of the ſaid Oath, the
ſaid Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner or Priſoners, ſhall upon any Indictment or Indictments,
or by his or their own Confeſſion, or Verdict of Twelve Men, be Convicted
of Falſe Swearing in any Point or Article contained in the ſaid Oath, as he
or they ſhall or may be by force of this Act, Then ſuch Priſoner or
Priſoners ſo Convicted as aforeſaid, ſhall ſuffer all ſuch Pains
and Forfeitures, as by the Statute of <hi>Quinto</hi> of Queen
<hi>Elizabeth,</hi> are to be inflicted upon any perſon Convicted of wilful
Perjury. And alſo the Court by Proceſs out of which the Priſoner was
Impriſoned, ſhall Award a <hi>Capias ad ſatisfaciendum infinite,</hi> or
other Proceſs, directed to any Sheriff or Sheriffs, for the Apprehending of
the ſaid Priſoner, and upon Return of <hi>Cepi Corpus,</hi> ſhall remand
the ſaid Prſoner into the Priſon whence he or ſhe was diſmiſſed,
there to remain in Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, in ſuch manner and condition as he or ſhe
was before his or her ſaid Enlargement; And then and from thenceforth he or
ſhe ſhall be adjudged to be in Execution fully, as if he or ſhe had never
been diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged thereof; And the Execution and Executions upon his or her
Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods and Chattels, if any ſuch happen to
be, after his or her ſaid Diſcharge out of Priſon, and before he or ſhe
ſhall be Remanded, ſhall ſtand alſo good and effectual in Law; Any Act,
Statute, or Cuſtom to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>Provided, and be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That
in caſe any Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Priſon, ſhall refuſe or delay
to Bring, or Diſcharge or ſet at Liberty any Priſoner according to the
Order of the Iuſtice or Iuſtices, to be made in manner as aforeſaid,
Every ſuch Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Priſon, ſhall forfeit and pay to
ſuch Priſoner detained contrary to ſuch Order, the Sum of One hundred
pounds, to be Recovered by Action of Debt in any Court of Record, and ſhall
be alſo ſubject to any Fine and Puniſhment, as the ſaid Iuſtices
ſhall Order or Award.</p>
               <p>And whereas it is found by common experience, That ſuch
perſon or perſons that are under Arreſts, or committed to the Cuſtody
of Sheriffs, Bayliffs, Goalers, Keepers of Priſons or Goals, are much
abuſed and wronged by extorting of great Fees, Rewards, and other Exactions,
and put to great Expences under pretences of favour, or otherwiſe, whereby
they are greatly oppreſſed, and many times ruined in their Eſtates: For
remedy thereof, Be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if any
<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nder-Sheriff, Bayliff, Serjeant at Mace, or other Officer or Miniſter
whatſoever, ſhall at any time or times hereafter, have in his or their
Cuſtody, any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, by virtue or colour of any Writ,
Proceſs, or other Warrant whatſoever, It ſhall not be lawful for ſuch
Officer or Officers to convey or carry, or cauſe to be conveyed or carried,
the ſaid perſon or perſons to any Tavern, Ale-houſe; or other Publick
Victualling or Drinking houſe, without the free and voluntary conſent of
the ſaid <pb n="4" facs="tcp:187888:4"/> 
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <pb n="5" facs="tcp:187888:4"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <pb n="6" facs="tcp:187888:5"/>perſon or perſons, ſo as to
charge ſuch Priſoner with any Sum of Money for any Wine, Beer, Ale,
Victuals, Tobacco, or any other things whatſoever, but what the ſaid
perſon or perſons ſhall call for, of his, her, or their own accord; And
ſhall not demand, take or receive, or cauſe to be demanded, taken or
received, directly or indirectly, any other or greater Sum or Sums, then what
by Law ought to be taken or demanded for ſuch Arreſt, Taking, or Wait<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
(until ſuch perſon or perſons ſhall have procured an Appearance, found
Bail, agreed with his or their Adverſaries, or be ſent to the proper Goal
belonging to the County, City, Town or Place where ſuch Arreſt or Taking
ſhall be) nor take and exact any other Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward or Gratuity, for ſo keeping
the ſaid perſon or perſons out of the Goal or Priſon, then what he,
ſhe, or they ſhall or will, of his, her, or their own accord, voluntarily
and freely give; Nor take nor receive any other or greater Sum or Sums for each
nights Lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or other expences, then what is reaſonable and fitting in
ſuch caſes, or ſhall be ſo adjudged by the next Iuſtice of the Peace,
or at the next Quarter Seſſions; And ſhall not cauſe or procure the
ſaid perſon or perſons to pay for any other Wine, Beer, Ale, Victuals,
Tobacco, or other things then what the ſaid perſon or perſons ſhall
voluntarily, particularly, and freely call for.</p>
               <p>And that every Vnder-Sheriff, Goaler, Keeper of Priſon or
Goal, and every perſon or perſons whatſoever, to whoſe Cuſtody any
per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons ſhall be delivered or committed, by virtue of any Writ
of Proceſs, or any pretence whatſoever, ſhall permit and ſuffer the
ſaid perſon or perſons, at his and their will and pleaſure, to ſend
for, and have any Beer, Ale, Victuals, and other neceſſary food, where, and
from whence they pleaſe; as alſo to have and uſe ſuch Bedding, Linen,
and other things, as the ſaid perſon or perſons ſhall think fit,
without any purloining, detaining or paying for the ſame, or any part
thereof; nor ſhall demand, take or receive of the ſaid perſon or
perſons, any other or greater Fee or Fees, whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, for his or their
Commitment, Releaſe, or Diſcharge, or for his, her, or their Chamber-rent,
then what is allowable by Law, until the ſame ſhall be Settled by Three
Iuſtices of the Peace, whereof one to be of the <hi>Quorum,</hi> of each
particular County, City, and Town corporate, in their ſeveral Precincts; And
for the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Counties of <hi>Middleſex</hi> and
<hi>Surrey,</hi> the Two Lords Chief Iuſtices of the <hi>Kings Bench</hi> and
<hi>Common Pleas,</hi> and the Lord Chief Baron, or any two of them, and the
Iuſtices of the Peace of the ſame, in their ſeveral Iuriſdictions.</p>
               <p>And likewiſe that the ſaid Lords Chief Iuſtices, Lord
Chief Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron, and Iuſtices of the Peace in their ſeveral Iuriſdictions,
and all Commiſſioners for Charitable <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſes, do uſe their beſt
endeavours and diligence to examine and find out the ſeveral Legacies, Gifts
and Bequeſts beſtowed and given for the Benefit and Advantage of the poor
priſoners for Debt, in the ſeveral Goals and Priſons in this Kingdom, and
to ſend for any Deeds, Wills, Writings, and Books of Accompts whatſoever,
and any perſon or perſons concerned therein, and to Examine them upon Oath,
to make true Diſcovery thereof, (which they have full Power and Authority
hereby to do) and the ſame ſo found out and aſcertained, to Order and
Settle in ſome manner and way, that the Priſoners hereafter may not be
defrauded, but receive the full Benefit thereof, according to the true intent
of the Donors.</p>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:187888:5"/>
               <p>And that theſe Accounts of the ſeveral Legacies, Gifts and
Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſts given and beſtowed upon the ſeveral Priſoners for Debt
with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in this Kingdom, and the ſeveral Rates of Fees, and the future
Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment of Priſons, be Signed and Confirmed by the Lord Chief Iuſtices,
and Lord Chief Baron, or any two of them for the time being, and the Iuſtices
of the Peace in <hi>London, Middleſex,</hi> and <hi>Surrey,</hi> and by the
Iudges for the ſeveral Circuits, and Iuſtices of the Peace for the time
being, in their ſeveral Precincts, and fairly written, and hung up in a Table
in every Goal and Priſon, before the Firſt day of <hi>November,</hi> One
thouſand fix hundred ſeventy and one, and likewiſe be Regiſtred by each
and every Clerk of the Peace within his or their particular Iurisdiction; And
after ſuch Eſtabliſhment, no other greater Fee or Fees then ſhall be
ſo Eſtabliſhed, ſhall be demanded or received.</p>
               <p>And whereas it is become the common practice of Goalers and
Keepers of <hi>Newgate,</hi> the <hi>Gatehouſe</hi> at
<hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and ſundry other Goals and Priſons, to Lodge
together in one Room or Chamber and Bed, Priſoners for Debt, and Felons,
whereby many times ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt Gentlemen, Tradeſmen and others, Priſoners for
Debt, are diſturbed and hindred in the Night-time from their natural Reſt,
by reaſon of their Fetters and Irons, and otherwiſe much offended and
troubled by their lewd and prophane Language and Diſcourſes, with moſt
horrid Curſing and Swearing (much accuſtomed to ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons) Be it
Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That it ſhall not be lawful hereafter
for any Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Goal or Priſon, to put, keep or lodge
Priſoners for Debt and Felons together in one Room or Chamber; but that they
ſhall be put, kept and lodged ſepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate and apart one from another, in
diſtinct Rooms, upon pain that he, ſhe or they which ſhall offend
againſt this Act, or the true intent and meaning thereof, or any part
thereof, ſhall forfeit and loſe his or her Office, Place or Employment, and
ſhall forfeit treble Damages to the Party grieved, to be recovered by virtue
of this Act; Any Law, Statute, Vſage, or Cuſtom to the contrary in any
wiſe notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="Act">
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:187888:6"/>
               <head>Anno XXX. CAROLI II. REGIS. An Act for the further Relief and Diſcharge of
Poor Diſtreſſed Priſoners for Debt.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas by an Act of this preſent Parliament, made in the Two
and twentieth and Three and twentieth years of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord
King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second (In ituled, <hi>An Act for Relief and
Releaſe of Poor Diſtreſſed Priſoners for Debt</hi>) Proviſion hath
been made for Relief and Releaſe of ſuch Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoners as were in Priſon
for Debt or Damages upon the Fourteenth day of <hi>April,</hi> One thouſand
ſix hundred ſeventy and one, in ſuch way and manner as in the ſaid Act
is provided and declared; Notwithſtanding which, the perſons of ſuch
Priſoners have not been diſcharged of their Impriſonments, the words
<hi>Debt</hi> or <hi>Damages</hi> mentioned in the ſaid Act, being
conſtrued doubtful, as not Warranting the Diſcharge of any Priſoner,
unleſs Charged in Execution.</p>
               <p>For Explanation whereof, and to ſupply other Defects which
have obſtructed the good ends and purpoſes of the ſaid Act, Be it now
Enacted by the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty, by and with the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice and
Conſent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and the Commons in this
preſent Parliament Aſſembled, and by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of the ſame, That
all perſons being in Priſon upon the Nine and twentieth day of
<hi>May,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy and eight, being the
Anniverſary day of His Majeſties Birth and happy Reſtauration, for Debt
or Damages, or for or upon any Action or Actions, or upon any Mean-Proceſs
for Debt, Account or Treſpaſs upon the Caſe, which Actions by
Proſecution of Law may be Iudg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments for Debt or Damages, or who have
Iudgments entred upon Record againſt them, or are Charged in Execution, or
Impriſoned upon Attachments for Debt, or upon Outlawries before or after
Iudgment for Debts, or upon any other Proceſs whatſoever iſſuing out of
any Court of Law or Equity, for the Cauſe of Debt or Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mages, or Coſts
only, whether the ſaid perſons were in Priſon up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the ſaid Fourteenth
day of <hi>April,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy and one, and have
taken the Oath in the ſaid Act mentioned, or have been Committed to Priſon
ſince that time, who ſhall take the Oath in the ſaid recited Act
mentioned, ſhall and may be Releaſed and Diſcharged from their
Impriſonments, in ſuch way and manner as ſuch as were in Priſon for
Debt or Damages upon the ſaid Four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of <hi>April,</hi> One
thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy and one, by the former Act were or might
have been, in caſe the ſaid Debt and Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mages had been aſcertained by
Iudgment.</p>
               <p>And all Iuſtices of the Peace within their ſeveral Counties
and Diviſions, are hereby Authorized and Impowered to put in Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:187888:6"/>all ſuch Powers, Directions and Authorities, for the full
Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leaſe and Diſcharge of ſuch perſons as were in Priſon on the
ſaid Fourteenth day of <hi>April,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy
and one, as aforeſaid, and of all ſuch other perſons as have been ſince
that time committed to Priſon, and are in Priſon on the ſaid Nine and
twentieth day of <hi>May,</hi> as aforeſaid, as the ſaid former Act hath
made and provided for the Releaſe and Diſcharge of ſuch who were in
Priſon for Debt or Damages upon the ſaid Fourteenth day of <hi>April,</hi>
One thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy and one, and every Clauſe, Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter and
Thing in the ſaid former Act contained, ſhall be conſtrued and taken to
the benefit and advantage of ſuch as ſhall be in Priſon upon the ſaid
Nine and twentieth day of <hi>May,</hi> One thouſand ſix hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred ſeventy
and eight, as fully and amply as by the ſaid Act it ought to have been, for
the Benefit and Diſcharge of ſuch as were in Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon on the ſaid
Fourteenth day of <hi>April,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venty and
one.</p>
               <p>And whereas by the ſaid former Act it is provided, That if any
Creditor ſhall inſiſt to have his Debtor continued in Priſon after he
hath taken the ſaid Oath, and will allow him a weekly Mainten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance to be
appointed by the Iuſtices of the Peace, not exceeding Eighteen pence the
week, the ſame Priſoner ſhall continue and be detained in Priſon: Be it
now Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That ſuch weekly Allowance ſhall
be paid to the Priſoner himſelf, and not to the Goal-keeper, or any other
perſon for him; and it with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſpace of Three Months after ſuch
weekly Allowance by any Creditor, no Eſtate of the Priſoner ſhall be
diſcovered or made out before Two Iuſtices of the Peace of that County and
Diviſion where the ſaid Priſoner is kept in Priſon, then the ſaid
Priſoner ſhall forthwith be diſcharged by Warrant under the Hands and
Seals of any Two Iuſtices of the Peace of the ſame County and Diviſion
where the ſaid Priſoner ſhall be ſo in Priſon, to the Keeper of
ſuch Priſon in that behalf directed, as fully and amply as if ſuch
Priſoner had been Diſcharged by the Iuſtices of the Peace at their
Quarter Seſſions, as in the ſaid recited Act is mentioned; and that then
and from thenceforth the ſaid weekly Allowance ſhall ceaſe and determine,
as if the ſame had never been made.</p>
               <p>And all Priſoners by this preſent Act, or by the ſaid
former Act Freed and Diſcharged from their Impriſonments, are hereby
Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quitted and Diſcharged of and from the payment of Chamber-Rent, and all
and every other Fee and Fees due to the Goaler or Keeper of ſuch Priſon or
Priſons in any manner or wiſe.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That no
Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoner Diſcharged out of Priſon by virtue of this preſent Act, or by
vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of the ſaid recited Act, ſhall at any time hereafter be
Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for or by reaſon of any Debt or Damages, or any Sum or Sums of
Money contracted or grown due to, or recovered by any perſon or perſons at
whoſe Suit the ſaid Priſoner did then ſtand Charged in any Priſon, or
any other perſon or perſons to whom ſuch Priſoner did give notice under
the Hand and Seal of ſome Iuſtice of the Peace of the ſame County, City
or Place, the ſpace of Fourty days before the time of his Diſcharge, of his
intention to receive the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of this Act, and of the way and courſe he
intended to take for obtaining the ſame, before the time of their
Diſcharges, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; But that upon any Arreſt for ſuch Debt,
Damages, or Sums of Money, it ſhall or may be lawful for them, ſhewing a
Duplicate <pb n="8" facs="tcp:187888:7"/> 
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:187888:7"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <pb n="10" facs="tcp:187888:8"/>of their Diſcharge under the Hands
and Seals of the Iuſtices of the Peace by whom they were Diſcharged, or of
any Two of them, or of ſuch Iuſtices of the Peace, in caſe ſuch
Priſoner be Diſcharged after an allowance of Maintenance by the Creditor
for Three Mouths, as aforeſaid, which the ſaid Iuſtices are hereby
required to give to every Priſoner ſo by them Diſcharged, to retain an
At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney to appear for them, and File Common Bail to every ſuch Action, and
Plead thereunto; ſo that the Plaintiff, if he pleaſe, may recover, and
enter Iudgment againſt ſuch Priſoner, to be executed and levied upon the
Lands, Tenements, Goods and Chattels of ſuch Priſoner ſo Diſcharged, as
aforeſaid, his or her Wearing Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parel, Furniture for his or her Dwelling
houſe, the ſaid Furniture not exceeding Ten pounds in value, and
neceſſary Tools for his or her Trade and Occupation only excepied, but not
upon the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of the Priſoner, the perſons of ſuch Priſoners being
hereby for ever Freed and Diſcharged from Impriſonment for any Debt,
Treſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs upon the Caſe, Duty, Sum or Sums of Money, or thing thereunto
relating, Contracted or due before the time of their Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge, having had
notice, as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>And be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That in caſe
any Sheriff, Goaler, and Keeper of Priſon ſhall refuſe and delay to bring
and Diſcharge, and ſet at Liberty any Priſoner or Priſoners, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
to the Order of the Iuſtice or Iuſtices of the Peace, made in purſuance
of this Act, or of the ſaid former recited Act: Every ſuch Goaler, Sheriff,
or Keeper of Priſon, ſhall forfeit and pay to ſuch Priſoners ſo
detained contrary to ſuch Order, the Sum of Twenty pounds, to be recovered by
Action of Debt in any of His Majeſties Courts of Record, and ſhall alſo
be ſubject to ſuch Fine and Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment as the ſaid Iuſtices of the
Peace ſhall upon complaint thereof to them made Order and Award.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That
upon any Action of Eſcape, or other Suit brought or to be brought againſt
any Iuſtice of the Peace, Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Priſon, for any
thing done in obedience to this Act, it ſhall and may be lawful to and for
any ſuch Iuſtice of the Peace, Sheriff, Goaler and Keeper of Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, to
plead the General Iſſue, and give this Act in Evidence, which ſhall be a
good and ſufficient Diſcharge, and ſhall ſave harmleſs every ſuch
Iuſtice of the Peace, Sheriff, Goaler or Keeper of Priſon plead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the
ſame; And if the Plaintiff in any ſuch Action ſhall be Non<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuited, or
Verdict paſs againſt him, the Defendant ſhall have double Coſts, to be
Taxed by the Court where ſuch Action is brought.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That the Diſcharge of any
verſon or perſons by virtue of this Act, ſhall not amount unto, or be
conſtrued to Free or Diſcharge any other perſon or perſons joyntly or
ſeverally bound for, or liable to anſwer or ſatisfie the ſaid Debt, or
any part thereof, either as Principal or Surety, but that ſuch other perſon
or perſons ſhall be liable to anſwer the ſaid Debt and Dama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges in
ſuch manner, to all intents and purpoſes, as they were before the
Diſcharge of ſuch Priſoner.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, That no perſon ſhall be Diſcharged by
this Act, that hath not, or ſhall not before ſuch Oath made, have remained
in Priſon by the ſpace of Six months.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, That no perſon by virtue of this Act ſhall
be Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged out of Priſon, who ſhall ſtand Charged in Execution with
more then the Sum of Five hundred pounds to any one perſon, Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipal Money,
and Damages.</p>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:187888:8"/>
               <p>Provided alſo, That no Creditor inſiſting to have his
Debtor con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued in Priſon, ſhall be bound to make any Weekly Allowance
for the Subſiſtance of the Priſoner, where the Father, Mother, Son or
Daughter, or other perſon who by the Laws of this Realm are bound to Maintain
him in Diſcharge of the Pariſh, if he were at large, are of ſufficient
Ability to Maintain ſuch Priſoner.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, and be it Enacted, That if any Creditor
inſiſting to have his Debtor continued in Priſon, and Ordered to make
Allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance towards his Maintenance, ſhall deſire to have his Debtor, being
a perſon formerly uſing any Handicraft or Day-labour, removed to any
publick Workhouſe, there to be kept at hard Labour, and ſhall within One
week next after notice of ſuch Order for making Allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance, at his own proper
Coſts and Charges, cauſe ſuch Priſoner by <hi>Habeas Corpus</hi> and
Commitment, or other Order, to be removed to any publick Workhouſe in the
ſame County where the ſaid Priſon is, or within Twenty miles diſtance
of the ſaid Priſon, That then ſuch Priſoner ſo removed to the ſaid
Workhouſe, ſhall and may be there held to Labour ſuitable to his Ability,
and the Creditor or Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors ſhall-afterwards contribute towards his
Maintenance, only ſuch Sum as over and above the profit of his Labour ſhall
be requiſite to Maintain him, to be aſcertained by the two next Iuſtices
of Peace; And in caſe the profit of his Labour ſhall exceed the value of
his Maintenance, One moiety of the overplus ſhall go towards the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of
his Debts for which he remains in Execution; the other Moiety ſhall be paid
to the hauds of the ſaid Priſoner, the ſaid Moie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties to be diſtributed
accordingly by the two next Iuſtices of the Peace.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted, That after any perſon ſhall by
virtue of this Act have continued at any Workhouſe by the ſpace of Two
years, he is then to be Diſcharged from his Impriſonment, and enjoy the
full Benefit of this Law.</p>
               <p>And be it Enacted, That any Iudge of ſuch Court whereto ſuch
Debtor is a Priſoner, or the two next Iuſtices of the Peace to ſuch
Workhouſe, ſhall and may have power to commit ſuch Debtor, being brought
before him or them by <hi>Habeas Corpus,</hi> or Order under the Hands and
Seals of two ſuch Iuſtices, unto any Workhouſe within the County where
ſuch Priſon is, there to remain according to this Act.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That if any Priſoner that
ſhall be Releaſed by virtue of this Act, ſhall at any time afterwards be
found or ſuſpected by any of his Creditors to have in ready Money, Goods or
Chattels in his own hands and poſſeſſion, or in the hands of any
others, to his or her uſe, or in Truſt for him or her, in value over and
above what he or ſhe is allowed by this or the ſaid former Act to have,
other then ſuch Goods in his Shop or Work-houſe as he ſhall have been
Credited or Truſted with ſince the time of his Diſcharge, and for what he
ſhall be really Indebted at the time of his making ſuch Oath, and he or
ſhe will not or do not upon convenient Demand, pay his or her Debt or Debts
therewith, as far as the ſame will reach, That then, and in ſuch caſe, at
the Requeſt of any Creditor, the ſaid Oath ſhall be tendred to him or her
again, by any Iuſtice of the Peace in this Act before Impowered to
Adminiſter the ſaid Oath for Diſcharge or Priſoners, or by any Iudge of
the Court wherein there is Iudg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment againſt him, which he or ſhe
refuſing to take, ſhall be Remanded to Priſon in Execution for ſuch
Debt or Debts; Any thing in this Act to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:187888:9"/>
               <p>Provided alſo, That this Act ſhall not extend to any
perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons in Execution for any Fine on him or her Impoſed for
any Offence committed before the ſaid Nine and twentieth day of <hi>May,</hi>
One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſix hundred ſeventy and eight.</p>
               <p>Provided that ſuch perſon or perſons as is or are detained
in Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon upon any Mean Proceſs, if it ſhall be deſired by any
Creditor, before any Iuſtice of the Peace to whom ſuch Priſoner hath
applied for his Diſcharge, ſhall forthwith give a Warrant to ſome
Attorney to Appear, or File common Bail for him or them, in the Court out of
which the ſaid Mean-Proceſs Iſſued, and to receive a Declaration at the
Plaintiffs Suit, and that ſuch Priſoner ſhall thereupon have the full
Benefit of this Law, as to the Liberty of his Perſon, againſt his ſaid
Impriſonment upon the ſaid Mean Proceſs, and againſt any Iudgment or
Execution that ſhall be had againſt him in that Suit, and againſt any
other Suit that ſhall be brought againſt him for the ſame Matter or
Cauſe of Action, to all intents and purpoſes, as ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and beneficially as
if he had been Charged in Execution at the ſaid Plaintiffs Suit before the
Nine and twentieth of <hi>May,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy and
eight; but ſuch Priſoner upon Mean-Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs, ſhall, in caſe of his
refuſal to give ſuch Warrant of Attorney, loſe the whole Benefit of this
Law.</p>
               <p>Provided always, That no Merchant Stranger, or other Alien or
Foreigner that hath been Arreſted, and is in Priſon on any Action or Suit,
for or by reaſon of any Debt, or other Engagement Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracted or Entred into
beyond the Seas, ſhall have any Benefit by this Act; but that all and every
ſuch Merchant Stranger, or other Alien or Foreigner, ſhall and may be
detained in Priſon, and proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed againſt as it this Act had never been
made.</p>
               <p>Provided always, That no Priſoner ſhall be Diſcharged by
virtue of this Act, until he ſhall before the Iuſtices of the Peace who are
by this Act Impowered to Diſcharge him, Declare upon his Corporal Oath (which
Oath the ſaid Iuſtices are hereby appointed to Adminiſter) what Effects
are belonging to him, or what Debt or Debts are then ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to him within any
of His Majeſties Dominions, or elſewhere, and by whom, and for what
Cauſe, and upon what Security; of all which a Schedule ſhall be made in the
preſence of ſuch Iuſtices, and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed by the Priſoner, and
ſhall be by ſuch Iuſtices Returned to the next Seſſions, there to be
kept for the better Information of the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors of ſuch Priſoner, who, or
ſuch of them as will joyn, may there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon Sue for ſuch Debts, or ſo much
thereof as will reaſonably ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfie them, in the name of the Priſoner,
and after the ſame Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered and Received, to render the overplus (their own
Debts and Charges firſt deducted) to the Priſoner.</p>
               <p>Provided always (and to deter all perſons who are by the
Chari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table intention of this Act to be Relieved, from abuſing the Favour
hereby to them intended) That if any perſon, who ſhall in purſuance of
this Act take this Oath for any of the purpoſes hereby appointed, ſhall
Forſwear or Perjure himſelf, Then ſuch perſon being thereof lawfully
Convicted, ſhall beyond, and over and above the Penalties which may by the
Law now in being be Indicted, ſuffer Impriſonment for the ſpace of Seven
years, without Bail or Mainpriſe.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:187888:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
